Finding Aid for the The Andrew Nelson Lytle Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Series II. Writings
  - Novels (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - The Velvet Horn. (2 of 2) 2 pages typed manuscript with holograph corrections, probably and early draft. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Reviews-Published (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - “A Ploughman’s Politics.” 2 off prints of a review of Arator: Being a Series of Agricultural Essays, Practical and Political: In Sixty-Four Numbers, by John Taylor of Caroline, edited by M.E. Bradford. Published in Modern Age, Summer, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Reviews-Published (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - “Is America Jeffersonian?” Clipping of a review of Thomas Jefferson: The Apostle of Americanism, by Gilbert Chinard. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Reviews-Unpublished (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Untitled. 6 pages holograph manuscript appears to be a review of Black April by Julia Peterkin, published in, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Short Stories-Published (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - “Jericho, Jericho, Jericho.” Holograph fragment on the back of an envelope, postmarked, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Short Stories-Unpublished (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - “The Baffling of Sherlock Holmes.” Pages 1-6, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Short Stories-Unpublished (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - “The Church With Only One Door.” Pages [1]-2 typed manuscript with holograph corrections, undated, but noted as written at “Cornsilk Farm, Guntersville, Alabama.” (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Short Stories-Unpublished (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - “The Mourning Dove.” Also titled “The Turkle Dove” and “The Death of the Turkle Dove.” Pages 1-4, unnumbered insert, 5-8, 8-12, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Speeches (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - “Can You Teach Creative Writing?” Pages 1-9, 16-19, 1-15, 15-18, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Speeches (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - “Southern Fiction: You’ve Got To Read It.” One page typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Speeches (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Untitled. Five page typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Possibly a speech given to the United Daughters of the Confederacy about Robert E. Lee. (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Speeches (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Untitled. Pages [1]-10, typed manuscript with holograph corrections, about what an artist is, what function he performs in society and what difficulties he faces, especially the Southern artist. (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Speeches (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Untitled. Two pages typed manuscript, a toast to Red Lancaster on his 75th birthday. (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - “The Gold Dust Family.” (1 of 3) Act I – Title page, cast of characters and synopsis of acts, pages [1]-36, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Not dated, but noted as being written at “Cornsilk Farm, Guntersville, Alabama,” possibly, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - “The Gold Dust Family.” (2 of 3) Act II – Pages [1]-41, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - “The Gold Dust Family.” (3 of 3) Act III – Pages [1]-20, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Also one holograph page numbered as page 9. (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - “The Gold Tooth.” Pages [1]-20, typed manuscript with holograph corrections, two sets, produced at Vanderbilt University in, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - “De Hind Tit.” Title page, cast of characters, pages 1-13, 13-23, typed manuscript. (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - “The Hind Teat.” Pages [1]-20, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - “The Keepers of the House.” Title page only. (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - “The Lost Sheep.” Title page (2), cast of characters, pages [1]-14, 17-22, 1-7, 9- 23, title page, 11, 15-19, 22, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Dated “copyright 1928,” gives addresses as “246 Sullivan St., New York City” and “503 Franklin St., Huntsville, Alabama.” Play produced at Yale (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - “New Ground.” (1 of 10) Scene I – Title page, cast of characters, synopsis of scenes, [1]-8, 8-25, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. Author shown is “K.L. Alexander,” a pseudonym (Lytle’s grandmother’s name through remarriage). (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - “New Ground.” (2 of 10) Scene I – Pages [1]-6, 8, 10-15, 19-24, [1], [1]-2, 2-3, 6, 19-23, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - “New Ground.” (3 of 10) Scene II – Pages [1]-21, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - “New Ground.” (4 of 10) Scene II – Pages [1]-9, 15, 17-22, [1]-7, 9-19, 19 typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - “New Ground.” (5 of 10) Scene III – Pages [1]-16, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - “New Ground.” (6 of 10) Scene III – Pages [1]-16, 11-20, 22-27, [1]-5, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - “New Ground.” (7 of 10) Scene IV – Pages [1]-17, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - “New Ground.” (8 of 10) Scene IV – Pages [1]-20, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - “New Ground.” (9 of 10) Scene V – Pages [1]-17, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Drama (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - “New Ground.” (10 of 10) Scene V – Pages [1]-2, 4, 6-7, 10-12, 10, 25, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Drama (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - “New Ground.” (1 of 8) Miscellaneous early drafts, holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Drama (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - “New Ground.” (2 of 8) Miscellaneous early drafts, holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Drama (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - “New Ground.” (3 of 8) Miscellaneous early drafts, holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Drama (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - “New Ground.” (4 of 8) Miscellaneous early drafts, holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Drama (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - “New Ground.” (5 of 8) Miscellaneous early drafts, holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Drama (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - “New Ground.” (6 of 8) Miscellaneous early drafts, holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Drama (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - “New Ground.” (7 of 8) Miscellaneous early drafts, holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Drama (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - “New Ground.” (8 of 8) Miscellaneous early drafts, holograph and typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Drama (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - “A Play on Jeff Davis.” 1 page holograph notes with an idea for a play about Jefferson Davis. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Drama (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - “Scalabag.” 3 page typed manuscript outline of a play, probably by Lytle. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Drama (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - “The Walls of Jerico.” Pages [1]-6, 2 unnumbered pages, [1]-4, 9 unnumbered pages, typed manuscript with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Fragments & Unidentified (1 of 9) (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified holograph and typed manuscript poems (5), at least some of which appear to be in Lytle’s hand, but which have not been positively identified as his. Titles or first lines (if untitled) as follows:, “As I strolled out one evening...” “A Dream” “Lay down the circling wreath, the moist...” “Marie” “The Nameless Maiden” (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Fragments & Unidentified (2 of 9) (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified typed manuscript of an essay or speech, pages 2-18, about words and language and the writer. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Fragments & Unidentified (3 of 9) (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Typed notes for an unidentified essay or speech, 3 pages, about writing, the writer’s purpose, the profession of writing. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Fragments & Unidentified (4 of 9) (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified typed manuscript fragment, pages 2, 4-5, 8-10, 12, 15, probably having to do with agrarianism. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Fragments & Unidentified (5 of 9) (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified typed manuscript fragment, 3 pages, probably having to do with agrarianism. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Fragments & Unidentified (6 of 9) (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified fragment, both holograph and typescript, 4 pages, mentions John Taylor, Jefferson, etc. Possibly belong to different manuscripts, but found together. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Fragments & Unidentified (7 of 9) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified typed manuscript fragment of a play, pages [1]-2, 5-14, 16-28, 32-41 probably by Lytle. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Fragments & Unidentified (8 of 9) (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Unidentified typescript fragment of a play, pages 1-8, probably by Lytle. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Fragments & Unidentified (9 of 9) (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified typescript fragment of a play, page 13, probably by Lytle. (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Research Material (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - At The Moon’s Inn. (1 of 2) Research material, notes, etc. Many of the notes appear to be on the backs of rejected manuscript pages of the novel. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Research Material (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - At The Moon’s Inn. (2 of 2) More of same, as above. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Research Material (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company. (1 of 4) Research material, notes, clippings, etc. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Research Material (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company. (2 of 4) Research material, notes, clippings, etc. (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Research Material (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company. (3 of 4) Research material, notes, clippings, etc. (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Research Material (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company. (4 of 4) Research material, notes, clippings, etc. (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Research Material (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Material on John Taylor and Arator. (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Research Material (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous research material. (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Series III. Literary Career
  - Bibliographies of Writings (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - 1 page holograph list of Lytle’s writings (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - 5 page typed checklist of Lytle’s writings (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - 15 page typed bibliography by Jack De Bellis, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Contracts (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company (Hernando de Soto), 1938 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company (Horses of the Night), 1946 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Virginia Quarterly Review (“Mr. McGregor”), 1958 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Howard University Press (“Mr. McGregor”), 1982 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Fugitive Group (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Materials concerning the Fugitive Reunion of 1956 – list of participants, calendar of events, check stub from grant. (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Publicity (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Press releases and clippings for:, At The Moon’s Inn The Long Night A Name For Evil A Novel, a Novella and Four Stories The Velvet Horn (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Reader’s Rep orts (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Two unsigned reader’s reports of At The Moon’s Inn (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Reviews of Writings (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - At The Moon’s Inn (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Reviews of Writings (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Reviews of Writings (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - The Hero with the Private Parts (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Reviews of Writings (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - The Long Night (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Reviews of Writings (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - A Name For Evil (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Reviews of Writings (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - A Novel, A Novella and Four Stories (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Reviews of Writings (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Stories, Alchemy and Others (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Reviews of Writings (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - The Velvet Horn (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Royalty Statements (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company (“Private War”), 1935 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company (The Long Night), 1937-1938, 1944, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company (At The Moon’s Inn), 1941-1944 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company (“Another Man’s House:), 1946 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company (A Name For Evil), 1947-1948 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Eyre & Spottiswoode, Ltd. (At The Moon’s Inn), 1943 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Green Key Press (Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company), 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Harper & Row (I’ll Take My Stand), 1962 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Kenyon College (“Alchemy”), 1942 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - McDowell, Obolensky, Inc. (The Velvet Horn), 1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - McDowell, Obolensky, Inc. (A Novel, A Novella and Four Stories), 1958-1959 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Minton Balch (Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company), 1931-1935 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Prentice-Hall (A Southern Vanguard, Allen Tate, ed.), 1947 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - G.P. Putnam’s Sons (Bedford Forrest and His Critter Company), 1938-1952 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - University of the South (“The Image As Guide To Meaning In The Historical Novel”), 1953 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Sewanee Review (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - “Some of the Steps Necessary in Publishing a Quarterly Literary Magazine,” pages 1-6, 9-11, typed with holograph corrections and comments. (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - “Persons Connected With The Sewanee Review,” 1 typed page, of staff and students. (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - “Sewanee Review Fellowships,” 1 typed page, of those recommended/invited. (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Fragments (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - “About Andrew Lytle” (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Alabama Writers Conclave – Constitution and By-Laws, 7 typed pages (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - National Free Lance Writers, Inc. of Orlando, FL. – Membership Card (Box 11, Folder 44)
- Series IV. Agrarians
  - Agrarians (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - “Memorandum,” 4 typed pages. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - “Minutes of Convention Held by the Committee for the Alliance of Agrarian and Distributist Groups at Nashville, TN, June 4-5, 1936,” 11 typed pages. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - “Arguments for the Formation of an Invisible Confederacy,” 1 typed page. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Series V. Academic Career
  - Conferences (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Writer’s Conference, Indiana University, brochure, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Twenty-Fifth Washington and Lee Seminar in Literature, Washington and Lee University, program, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Twenty-Ninth Washington and Lee Seminar in Literature (“The Working Novelist and the Mythmaking Process” by Andrew Nelson Lytle), Washington and Lee University, program and announcement, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Writer’s Workshop, Morehead State College, brochure, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - A Hometown Symposium: Evelyn Scott and Caroline Gordon, Austin Peay State University, program, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Conference on Myth, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, program, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Financial (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Austin Peay State University, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Harvard Summer School, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Guggenheim Fellowship Grant, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Kenyon Review Fellowship, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - National Endowment for the Arts Grant Application, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - TIAA-CREF Statement, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - University of California, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - University of Florida, 1958-1959 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - University of Georgia, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - University of Oregon, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - University of the South, 1963, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - University of Florida (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Contracts, 1952, 1954, and 1956 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Graduate School, Admission to Candidacy Forms, 1954-1960 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Fragments (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Calendar for 1960 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - “Modes of the Short Story” (Syllabus?), p.2 only (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous poems by others (probably used in class to read from or as handouts) (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Series VI. Acting Career
  - Clippings (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - “The Gold Tooth,” by Andrew Nelson Lytle, Vanderbilt University, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - “The Patriarch,” by Boyd M. Smith, Yale University, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - “The Patrician,” author unidentified, Yale University, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - “The Dover Road,” by A.A. Milne, University Players, Southampton, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - “Pueblo,” by Covington Little, Yale University, [1928] (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Unnamed Play, [possibly “The Lost Sheep,” by Andrew Nelson Lytle] Murfreesboro Kiwanis Club, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Programs (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - “The Rivals,” by Richard Brinsley Sheridan, Centennial Club, Nashville, 1924. Performed by the Vanderbilt Players, including Lytle. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - “Les Deux Timides,” by Labiche, Alliance Francaise, Centennial Club, Nashville, 1925. Lytle included as performer. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - “The Gold Tooth,” by Andrew Nelson Lytle, Little Theatre, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, 1925. Performed by the Calumet Players. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - [Lazy By Divine Right], by Leila A. Wade, Yale University, 1927. Lytle included as performer. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - “The Dover Road,” by A.A. Milne, University Players, Southampton, 1927. Lytle included as performer. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - “The Lost Sheep,” by Andrew Nelson Lytle, Yale University, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - “The Last Mile,” by John Wexley, Sam H. Harris Theatre, [1930] (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Series VII. Biographical/Personal
  - Clippings (1 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Biographical, [1928]-[1987] (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Clippings (2 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - 1929-1987 and undated. Topics include Turkeys, Who Owns America (ed. Herbert Agar), John Crowe Ransom, Allen Tate, Caroline Gordon, Huey Long, Frank Owsley, Fugitive Reunion, Peter Taylor, Civil War, Enrico Caruso, Donald Davidson, Julia Meek Gerety, University of the South. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Financial (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Banking. (1 of 4) Check Registers, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Financial (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Banking. (2 of 4) Check Registers, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Financial (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Banking (3 of 4) Check Registers, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Financial (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Banking (4 of 4) Check Registers, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Financial (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Banking, statements and cancelled checks, 1926-1964 (most dated 1959-1960). (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Financial (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Bills/Receipts, 1924-1988 (most dated 1957-1961). (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Financial (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Farming, Tobacco Quotas, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Financial (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Insurance. Property, Medical and Life, 1952-1960, and undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Financial (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Investments. Stock certificates, 1933-1988 (most 1958-1960). (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Financial (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Loans & Notes, 1943-1955, and undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Financial (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Medical. Bills, receipts and claims, 1958-1988 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Financial (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Property Records. Deeds and mortgages, 1932-1960 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Financial (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Ration Books. World War II rations books. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Financial (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Taxes. Property and income, 1956-1963 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Invitations (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - 1927-1988, and undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Monteagle Sunday School Assembly (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - By-Laws, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Officers, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Photographs (1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - 1924-198[?], mostly of the immediate Lytle family. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Photographs (2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Primarily photos of others (including Donald Davidson and Allen Tate), houses, farms, other Lytle family members and unidentified. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Recipes (1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, handwritten recipes (loose and in books) and small recipe books. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Recipes (2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Clippings, handwritten recipes (loose and in books) and small recipe books. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Student Days (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Typed notes on grammar, Coleridge, Wordsworth. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Travels (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - European. German Currency, circa 1922-1923. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Travels (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - European. Itinerary for American Student Friendship Tour, 1924 (France, Switzerland, Austria, Germany, Poland, Denmark, England) (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Program for Welcome Ceremony, July 23, 1924, Munich. (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - List of Pictures (402) (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Travels (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - European. Lytle’s Journal of his European Trip, July 1-August 24, 1924. 43 typed and holograph pages. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Travels (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Other. Hotel receipts, airline tickets, travel vouchers, etc., 1953-1961 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Fragments (1 of 3) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1930-1987, and undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Fragments (2 of 3) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1930-1987, and undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Fragments (3 of 3) (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 1930-1987, and undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Series VIII. Family Papers
  - Clippings (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Deaths, marriages, etc., 1921-1945 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Diaries (1 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Edna Langdon Barker, 1930-1934 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - “Kate and Jane,” 1961 (Katherine Anne Lytle?). (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Diaries (2 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Diaries (3 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Diaries (4 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Diaries (5 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Diaries (6 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Diaries (7 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Diaries (8 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Diaries (9 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Diaries (10 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Diaries (11 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Diaries (12 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Diaries (13 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Diaries (14 of 14) (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Documents (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Report cards, 1892-1962. (Joe Nelson, Pamela Lytle, Katherine Lytle) Certificate of Confirmation, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Financial (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Stock certificate, checks, bills, receipts, etc., 1860-1947 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Genealogical (1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Lytle Family, Nelson Family, Taylor Family, Day Family, Calvert Family, Morton Family. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Genealogical (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Lytle Family, Nelson Family, Taylor Family, Day Family, Calvert Family, Morton Family (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Insurance (Box 15, Folder 5)